CHRISTOPHER RANDALL

Chris.f.Randall@gmail.com • <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>Github</u> • <u>Website</u> Houston, Texas • (713) 306-7991

Full Stack Engineer

I am a full-stack software engineer with a background in leadership. I have extensive experience coding in multiple languages, working with various frameworks ranging from React to Rails, and learning new languages in a short period of time. I thrive under pressure, am extremely self-motivated, work well with others, love formula one, soccer, cooking, reading, and learning new things.

Technical Skills

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, React-Native, Redux, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Git, SQLite, Postgres, Heroku, Java, Python

EXPERIENCE

Eagle Global Advisors - Intern; Houston, TX

May 2019 - August 2019

- Constructed and presented weekly reports concerning popular new companies around the globe and their growth potential
- Researched and analyzed potential artificial intelligence cybersecurity companies in Israel, Germany, and the United States

Hilcorp Energy Company - IT, Tech, and Software Intern; Houston, TX

May 2018 - August 2018

- Repaired, updated, and replaced laptops, desktops, printers, for employees both in the office building and in the field
- Solved software problems and presented tech solutions for current company problems revolving around cyber security

Dynamic Health Solutions - *Data-Sorting Intern;* Houston, TX

July 2017 - August 2017

Queried large medical data sets using SQL to find specific data and then created graphical representations for employes

PROJECTS

Parking Application (Pavement) - Github

August 2022

- Deployed a full stack react and ruby + rails application with a reservation system, google maps integration, and user auth
- Used Ruby on rails 7.0, PostgreSQL, Tailwind and Tailwind UI, StimulusJS, Turbo, and Stripe for payment processing

Sixtle React App - Github - Demo

July 2022

• Designed and programmed a wordle style react app revolving around six letter words using Context API, React, and CSS

Chat Messaging Application (Prattle) - Github - Demo

July 2022

- Co-programmed react frontend with ruby + rails backend enabling user authentication, direct messaging, and chat groups
- Implemented web sockets, enabling real time messaging, channel creation, and a settings button altering tailwind for user

2048 React App - Github

June 2022

• Created a react and tailwind application replicating the game 2048 while using ruby on rails for user authentication

Social Media App (Exquisite Exhibit) - Github

August 2022

- Produced a react and tailwind frontend using react masonry, context API, navigation, and email form assistance tickets
- Designed a ruby on rails backend with postgresql and implemented full CRUD operations for posts, users, comments, likes

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AND ACTIVITIES

National Outdoor Leadership School

May 2017 – July 2017

- Selected to serve as a leader of a four-night trek through deep wilderness in the Lemhi Mountain Range
- Developed leadership, communication, and survival skills while camping for two months in remote mountain ranges

Recruitment and Social Chair

Fall 2017 - Spring 2018

Assisted in budgeting \$25 thousand fraternity funds, organized social events, and lead weekly meetings for the fraternity

EDUCATION

The University of Houston	with a capstone in Data Science Overall GPA: 3.523	December 2021
Flatiron	Software Bootcamp focusing on React, JS, HTML, Ruby + Rails	August 2022